[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "Which of the following is incorrect about core temperature",
    "options": [
      "It is constant",
      "It is 37.8◦c",
      "It is derived by deep seated body tissues",
      "It is derived from the superficial part of the body"
    ],
    "answer": ["It is derived from the superficial part of the body"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "Which of the following is correct about skin temperature",
    "options": [
      "it is constant",
      "heat generated is transmitted to superficial parts of the body",
      "it is derived by seated body tissues",
      "it has a temperature of 39◦c"
    ],
    "answer": [
      "heat generated is transmitted to superficial parts of the body"
    ],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Temperature Regulation"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "Skin temperature can be measured at strategic places such as:",
    "options": [
      "oral",
      "axillary",
      "rectal",
      "sublingually",
      "all of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["all of the above"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Temperature Regulation"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "The pathological variations of temperature include",
    "options": [
      "hypothermia",
      "hyperthermia",
      "menstrual cycle",
      "sleep",
      "option Aand B are correct"
    ],
    "answer": ["option Aand B are correct"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Temperature Regulation"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "Physisological variations of temperature include the following except",
    "options": ["before meal", "after meal", "age", "exercise", "sex"],
    "answer": ["before meal"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Temperature Regulation"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "Physiological variations of temperature include the following except",
    "options": [
      "sleep",
      "diurnal changes",
      "age",
      "secretory phase",
      "ovulatory phase"
    ],
    "answer": ["secretory phase"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Temperature Regulation"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "Which of the following statements are incorrect",
    "options": [
      "muscle accounts for 80% of body temperature",
      "females have more brown fats",
      "temperature is increased in infants",
      "during sleep temperature increases",
      "temperature is reduced in adult"
    ],
    "answer": ["during sleep temperature increases"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Temperature Regulation"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "The following cause increase in temperature except",
    "options": ["exercise", "emotion", "sex", "sleep", "Nocturnal changes"],
    "answer": ["sleep"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Temperature Regulation"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "When heat production = heat loss it causes",
    "options": [
      "normal temperature",
      "increase in temperature",
      "decrease in temperature",
      "fever",
      "option B and D are correct"
    ],
    "answer": ["normal temperature"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Temperature Regulation"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "When heat production > heat loss it leads to",
    "options": [
      "normal temperature",
      "increase in temperature",
      "decrease in temperature",
      "fever",
      "option B and D are correct"
    ],
    "answer": ["increase in temperature"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Temperature Regulation"
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "When heat production < heat loss it leads to",
    "options": [
      "normal temperature",
      "increase in temperature",
      "decrease in temperature",
      "fever",
      "option B and D are correc"
    ],
    "answer": ["decrease in temperature"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Temperature Regulation"
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "Extra metabolism include",
    "options": [
      "testosterone",
      "growth hormone",
      "epinephrine and nor epinephrine",
      "T4",
      "all of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["all of the above"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Temperature Regulation"
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "Extra metabolism include",
    "options": [
      "testosterone",
      "growth hormone",
      "increased cellular activities",
      "T4",
      "all of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["all of the above"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Temperature Regulation"
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "_________accounts for majority of heat loss",
    "options": ["conduction", "convection", "radiation", "all of the above"],
    "answer": ["radiation"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Temperature Regulation"
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "Insensible heat loss occur in places like",
    "options": ["lungs", "skin", "brain", "option A and C", "option Aand B"],
    "answer": ["option A and C"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Temperature Regulation"
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "question": "Posterior hypothalamus causes",
    "options": [
      "vasoconstriction",
      "inhibits sweating",
      "increase hormonal metabolism",
      "increase cellular activities",
      "shivering"
    ],
    "answer": ["shivering"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Temperature Regulation"
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "question": "The human body temperature is maintained at a set point of",
    "options": ["34.5◦c", "35.5 ◦c", "36.5◦c", "37.5◦c", "38.5◦c"],
    "answer": ["37.5◦c"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Temperature Regulation"
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "question": "The normal body temperature ranges from",
    "options": [
      "36.2 - 36.8◦c",
      "36.2 - 37.8◦c",
      "37.2 - 38.8◦c",
      "38.2 - 39. 8◦c",
      "39.2 - 40.8◦c"
    ],
    "answer": ["36.2 - 37.8◦c"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Temperature Regulation"
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "question": "Pyrogens that induces fever casue one of the following",
    "options": [
      "decrease in production of interleukin",
      "shivering",
      "decrease in hypothalamic set point",
      "vasodilation of blood vessels in the skin",
      "both A and D"
    ],
    "answer": ["shivering"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Temperature Regulation"
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "question": "The human temperature regulating area is loctated at",
    "options": [
      "the cerebral cortex",
      "the temporal lobe",
      "the thalamus",
      "the hypothalamus",
      "the medulla oblongata"
    ],
    "answer": ["the hypothalamus"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Temperature Regulation"
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "question": "The thermoregulatry response controlled by the cholinergic sympathetic system",
    "options": [
      "shivering",
      "brown adipose tissue thermogenesis",
      "thyroid hormone secretion",
      "thermoregulatory behavior",
      "sweating"
    ],
    "answer": ["sweating"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Temperature Regulation"
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "question": "Homeothermals stand for animals with",
    "options": [
      "stable body temperature",
      "unstable body temperature",
      "body temperature changing with environment",
      "body temperature similar to cold blood animals",
      "body temperature that is unpredictable"
    ],
    "answer": ["stable body temperature"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Temperature Regulation"
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "question": "Hard exercise results in body temperature with the range of",
    "options": [
      "36 to 37◦c",
      "37 to 38◦c",
      "38 to 40◦c",
      "40 to 42◦c",
      "36 to 36.2◦c"
    ],
    "answer": ["38 to 40◦c"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Temperature Regulation"
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "question": "Clinical thermometer measure body temeperature after a minimum of",
    "options": ["2 minute", "½ minute", "3 minutes", "4 minuites", "5 minutes"],
    "answer": ["½ minute"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Temperature Regulation"
  },
  {
    "id": 25,
    "question": "Heat gain include all these except",
    "options": [
      "metabolism",
      "environment",
      "shivering",
      "evaporation",
      "hot food"
    ],
    "answer": ["evaporation"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Temperature Regulation"
  },
  {
    "id": 26,
    "question": "Heat loss mechanisms include all these except",
    "options": [
      "conduction",
      "convection",
      "radiation",
      "metabolism",
      "evaporation"
    ],
    "answer": ["metabolism"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Temperature Regulation"
  },
  {
    "id": 27,
    "question": "Eccrine sweating produces the following",
    "options": ["NaCl", "proteins", "lead", "magnesium", "calcium"],
    "answer": ["NaCl"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Temperature Regulation"
  },
  {
    "id": 28,
    "question": "Apocrine has a significant content of one of these materials- which one",
    "options": ["sodium", "chloride", "calcium", "magnesium", "proteins"],
    "answer": ["proteins"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Temperature Regulation"
  },
  {
    "id": 29,
    "question": "Body temperature is maintained in a room with decreasing temperature by all these except",
    "options": [
      "curling up",
      "vasoconstriction",
      "shivering",
      "cold food and drinks",
      "exercise"
    ],
    "answer": ["cold food and drinks"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Temperature Regulation"
  },
  {
    "id": 30,
    "question": "Body heat is decreased by all these except",
    "options": [
      "vasodilation of skin vessels",
      "sweating",
      "putting on cooler clothes",
      "increased muscle tone",
      "putting on fan"
    ],
    "answer": ["increased muscle tone"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Temperature Regulation"
  }
]
